You guys will come to another video, so in this we will explore one of the next-gen
network detections that will be widely used in every organization based on cyber security.
So, if they are a product based company they will be have a NDR network detections and
response. So, basically this tool, this software or tool this will monitor each and every
network traffic and it will detect a species traffic and it will respond based on that like
blocking that IP and these things ok. So, it has some artificial intelligence
and machine learning capabilities based on that it will investigate each and every
network traffic and it will decide whether the traffic is malicious or a good traffic ok based
on that. So, sometime you may know so many of the threads it will bypass the antivirus
software and firewalls. So, but the network detection and response this is the next-gen
AV, next-gen tool or AV with the artificial intelligence and machine learning capabilities
so it will easily stop that threads ok. So, it is a network traffic monitoring and behavior
on analysis. So, it will monitor each and every machine. So, what was the behavior of
that if there is any changes in a behavior like a huge network traffic from a machine then
it will monitor that and it will see whether it was a bot nuts or it is a bot nut activity
or any other DAWS attack or DAWS it was trying ok and it will respond based on that.
Also, you can do an instant response from this tool you can if the IP was malicious you
can take an IP and you can block that in the NDR also or you can add any rules in that
in NDR. So, it will be a very helpful coming to in cybersecurity based network defense tools
ok. So, this is one of the powerful tool which will be used to network to stop the advanced
threads from the attacker ok. So, the NDR rules the logs will be like that. So, the source
IP destination IP and how many bytes are sent and how many bytes are received and who
is the users and who orders the host names and everything it will be have a great great
and great log functions. It will log everything each and every IP. So, based on the rules
so, we know the firewall have an inbound and outbound rules. So, the NDR also have some
set of rules the set of policies. So, based on the policy it will block or allow the network
traffic otherwise it will. So, the IP was malicious so, it will block that otherwise it
will allow the network traffic. So, that is all about this section. So, we have seen
a lot and lot of tools that was widely used in organization. So, currently this NDR will
be used most of the organizations to stop the network based advanced threads like C2C
botnets, dots, details, everything we can see ok. So, let us complete this section and
we will move it to the next section. Thank you and we will share each and every resource
the PPT in the next session. Bye bye.